<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Ucm | My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://noppanit.github.io/blog/categories/ucm/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://noppanit.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-10-01T15:52:09-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://noppanit.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Your Name]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Oracle UCM (Document Management)]]></title>
    <link href="http://noppanit.github.io/oracle-ucm-document-management/"/>
    <updated>2008-05-27T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://noppanit.github.io/oracle-ucm-document-management</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, actually I have another 4 drafts left, but I will start to write this one first because I want to write it down before I forget it. This topid is about <a href="http://www.oracle.com/products/middleware/content-management/universal-content-management.html" target="_blank">Oracle Content Management</a>??which I was trained a week ago. Interestingly, when I was working at the first company, I had to implement our own Document Management System. So, I pretty have experience based on this product.</p>

<p>A week ago, I was sent to train about UCM, Universal Content Management, which has another 5-6 features to be added on UCM. I was trained about Document Management.</p>

<p>The UCM can handle loads of document. They can be classified into catogory. They can be checked in, or out. It&#8217;s like keeping record of every version user check-in or out the document. And the most improtance part of Document Management is searching. While you want to keep your documents into a FileServer and you cannot retrieve them at all. So, searching is vital feature. UCM comes up with full-texted search and it can be changed to be metadata search, depend on your requirements.</p>

<p>The basic is, user check-in the document and it will be stored on the server and secured. When another user wants to check-out the document, which he/she has to have the right permission to deal with the document. He/She can check-out the document, which UCM will keep track on every document, versioning.</p>

<p>I have to say that the most interesting part of UCM is IRM, <a href="http://www.oracle.com/newsletters/information-indepth/content-management/sep-07/irm.html" target="_blank">Information Rights Management</a>. When a user check-out a document. How the company can keep track on that document, because that user can do anything on that document, print it, edit it, etc. So, IRM comes up to help the document when it is off the UCM server.</p>

<p>This topic is briefly.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
