<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: travel | My Blog]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/blog/categories/travel/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-12-30T20:57:23-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.noppanit.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Noppanit Charassinvichai]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[What should you expect for Salkantay trek to Machu Picchu]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/what-should-you-expect-for-salkantay-trek-to-machu-picchu/"/>
    <updated>2015-05-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.noppanit.com/what-should-you-expect-for-salkantay-trek-to-machu-picchu</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I’m not really a travel blogger but I’ll try to share my experience as much as possible. I’ve just come back from Peru (Machu Picchu). Me and a bunch of my friends did the Salkantay trek which hike from Cusco (sort of) to Machu Picchu. It’s a 5 days 4 nights trip. The hike is really challenging physically and mentally. You will experience altitude sickness and soreness from your body. Funny thing is I didn’t feel a thing at the highest peak, some of my friends experienced different symptoms. One of the best I’ve heard is; “It’s like EDM concert banging in my head”.</p>

<h2 id="stay-warm">Stay warm</h2>

<p>You really need to dress warm because you will be walking at the altitude around 14,000 feet which is going to be quite cold. I’d suggest a lot of layers instead of big puffy jacket. Base layer is really important and a good fleece. One thing that you can’t miss out is a good pair of wool socks.</p>

<h2 id="prepare-for-the-rain">Prepare for the rain</h2>

<p>It’s going to rain. What you really need is a good rain jacket and or Pancho is you want. I find rain jacket is enough to keep you dry. However, what really important is waterproof hiking shoes or you need extra pairs of socks. If you have your camera, rain cover for your bag and camera are really crucial.</p>

<h2 id="prepare-for-the-altitude">Prepare for the altitude</h2>

<p>If you think you will be affected by the altitude, please consult with your doctor to get some pills. I didn’t really get any headache while hiking on the high altitude but everybody is different.</p>

<h2 id="what-you-don8217t-really-need">What you don’t really need</h2>

<p>Water is what you really need. But you can get water at every stop along the trail. What you don’t really need is water purification. However, it’s just a small pack if you don’t mind carrying that.</p>

<h2 id="pack-light">Pack light</h2>

<p>I found myself overpack for the hike and I exhausted myself on the third day. If you think you’re going to need snacks. I suggest having <a href="http://www.starburst.com/">starburst</a>. My friend gave away two starbursts at every stop point which I think they really keep me going in terms of energy. I had my raw almonds and dry berries which helped a lot.</p>

<h2 id="sleep-comfy">Sleep comfy</h2>

<p>Sleeping bag is a must. However, I had a really good night sleep with my <a href="http://www.rei.com/product/866771/sea-to-summit-aeros-pillow-premium">camping pillow</a> and it’s inflatable and really light.</p>

<h2 id="taking-pictures-of-the-locals">Taking pictures of the locals</h2>

<p>If you walk around in Cusco, you might find local people dressing in traditional custom. If you take a picture of them, they might ask you for some money. I gave them 1 soles and it was enough. And make sure you ask their permission before you take a picture of them.</p>

<p><a data-flickr-embed="true" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/pinkcarnation/17626431306/in/dateposted-ff/" title="Peru-1093710.jpg"><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8837/17626431306_853767fc9e_z.jpg" width="640" height="423" alt="Peru-1093710.jpg" /></a><script async="" src="//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>

<h2 id="coca-leaves">Coca leaves</h2>

<p>The locals told us to chew coca leaves to prevent the tiredness and altitude sickness. To be honest, they didn’t help much but I really like the coca tea in the morning.</p>

<p><a data-flickr-embed="true" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/pinkcarnation/17465382290/in/dateposted-ff/" title="Peru-1093841.jpg"><img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7770/17465382290_7dfcc888d1_z.jpg" width="640" height="431" alt="Peru-1093841.jpg" /></a><script async="" src="//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>

<h2 id="local-food">Local food</h2>

<p>Peruvian cuisine is really interesting or at least from my point of view. I had Guinea pig and Alpaca. I like Alpaca but the Guinea pig is not really my jam. At least I tried.</p>

<p><a data-flickr-embed="true" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/pinkcarnation/17627373766/in/dateposted-ff/" title="Peru-1094221.jpg"><img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5441/17627373766_e4568e063a_z.jpg" width="640" height="444" alt="Peru-1094221.jpg" /></a><script async="" src="//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>

<h2 id="machu-picchu">Machu Picchu</h2>

<p><a data-flickr-embed="true" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/pinkcarnation/17653773851/in/dateposted-ff/" title="Peru-1094213.jpg"><img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8707/17653773851_aa6c40a15e_z.jpg" width="640" height="431" alt="Peru-1094213.jpg" /></a><script async="" src="//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>

<h2 id="good-view-from-your-tent">Good view from your tent</h2>

<p><a data-flickr-embed="true" href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/pinkcarnation/17653136981/in/dateposted-ff/" title="Peru-1093869.jpg"><img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7656/17653136981_03874afb08_z.jpg" width="640" height="431" alt="Peru-1093869.jpg" /></a><script async="" src="//embedr.flickr.com/assets/client-code.js" charset="utf-8"></script></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ziferblat, Pay-per-minute cafe in Moscow, Russia.]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/ziferblat-pay-per-minute-cafe-moscow-russia/"/>
    <updated>2014-05-18T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.noppanit.com/ziferblat-pay-per-minute-cafe-moscow-russia</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you’re in Moscow and you want somewhere to just sit down and catch up with some stuff. Or you just want to have a place to read. I recommend <a href="http://pushkin.ziferblat.net/en/" title="Ziferblat">Ziferblat</a>, it’s pay-per-minute cafe in Central Moscow.</p>

<p>Just 5-min walk from Tverskaya Station (Тверская). Then look for this sign.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.noppanit.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/Screen-Shot-2014-05-18-at-22.52.43.png"></p>

<p>You have to ring the bell and the security guard will buzz you in then you have to walk upstairs (2nd floor). Unfortunately, at least when I was there people speak little English but understandable. Also, the people are really friendly over there. You just need to tell your name and pay at the end when you’re ready to rome Moscow again.</p>

<p><img src="https://www.noppanit.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/05/Screen-Shot-2014-05-18-at-23.08.45.png"></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bouldering gym in Kadıköy, Istanbul]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/bouldering-gym-kadikoy-istanbul/"/>
    <updated>2014-03-02T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.noppanit.com/bouldering-gym-kadikoy-istanbul</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I would like to just contribute more to the bouldering in Istanbul. Since, I have been in Istanbul for over a month and I like bouldering. However, after a bit of searching I found little information about bouldering gyms in Istanbul. So far, I have been to two gyms and I’d like to share one of them first.</p>

<p>It’s called <a href="http://www.boulderistanbul.com/" title="boulder istanbul">Boulder Istanbul</a>.</p>

<p><strong>How to get there</strong><br />
This one is quite easy to get to and the location on the map below is quite accurate. I have checked in myself.</p>

<p>You can get the metro to Kadıköy and then walk from there for only 10-15 minutes or you can get the metrobus to Söğütlüçeşme which is the terminal station at the Asian side and then walk for 15-20 minutes. It’s quite a nice walk through kebab shops.</p>

<p><strong>Some pics</strong></p>

<p><img src="https://www.noppanit.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/20140302_141441.jpg"></p>

<p><img src="https://www.noppanit.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/20140302_141348.jpg"></p>

<p><img src="https://www.noppanit.com/wp-content/uploads/2014/03/20140302_141636.jpg"></p>

<p><strong>Price</strong><br />
It’s only 15 TL for a day pass.</p>

<p><strong>Official address</strong><br />
<span class="adr"><br /> <span class="street-address">Nüzhetefendi Sokak No:54 (Rıhtım caddesinin 3 üst paraleli)</span><br /> <span class="locality">Kadıköy</span>&lt;/br&gt;<br /> <span class="region">Istanbul</span><br /> </span></p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[You have never been clean, if you haven&#8217;t been to the Turkish bath.]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/never-clean-havent-turkish-bath/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-27T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.noppanit.com/never-clean-havent-turkish-bath</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Istanbul is the next closest thing I could come during Christmas. It’s just 4-hour from London and it’s a fantastic place to visit. I know when you think about Turkey you would think about the mosques, markets and kebap. There’s nothing wrong with that and I really enjoy walking around the buzzling Grand Bazaar (Büyük Çarşı). But there’s one thing I think everybody should be doing while you’re in Turkey is the Turkish bath.</p>

<p>There’s a saying I don’t remember who so I couldn’t quote here. “You have never been clean, if you haven’t been to the Turkish bath” and I think it’s really true.</p>

<p>Some people might say, I wouldn’t want a sweaty dude to scrub or massage yourself. But I think you should try everything until you can say you hate it.</p>

<p>So, I have scouted over the Internet and I found the article from the <a href="http://www.theguardian.com/travel/2013/mar/22/istanbul-karakoy-top-10-cafes-shops-galleries" title="guardian">Guardian</a> and <a href="http://www.tripadvisor.co.uk/Attraction_Review-g293974-d3626134-Reviews-Kilic_Ali_Pasa_Hamami-Istanbul.html" title="trip advisor">Trip Advisor</a>. I found this place <a href="http://kilicalipasahamami.com/">Kilic Ali Pasa</a>. So, I booked the place.</p>

<p>The first experience when you walked in, you will be greeted with a welcome drink and the staff will be giving you choices. You can choose to scrub yourself or you can have somebody to help you. After that, you change clothes to just the towel then the staff will guide you to Göbektaşı; the room with a big marble table in the middle. You will heat yourself up to be ready. The staff will pour hot and warm water to get your body ready then he will make you embarrassed by exfoliating your body from head to toe. I shower twice a day and I can still see my dead skin coming off. Then the staff will start the Köpük which is bubble soap wash. Then he will massage you a bit. After, everything is done he will lead you to the lounge area where you can sit and relax for as long as you want. You can you the bath again as many times as you want as well.</p>

<p>It’s a very relaxing bath and I think everybody should try at least for once so you will know whether you like it. I know I will come back for another Hamami for sure.</p>

<p>A little tip or actually my own mistake, bring your clean clothes with you or if you want to put on your dirty clothes when you’re super clean.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Paris 2013: Food quest.]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/paris-2013-food-quest/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.noppanit.com/paris-2013-food-quest</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have been asked from my friend if I could take him to Paris and show him around what cafes in Paris look like. He opens a <a href="http://www.verdeandco.co.uk/" title="Verde and Co.">sandwich shop</a> in London, Liverpool Street. It is a French style coffee shop where people line up for sandwiches and good chocolate. The shop is decorated with loads of French and Italian products.</p>

<p>So, I started to list out some of the most famous cafes in Paris. We have been to <a href="http://www.lebestofparis.com/best-restaurants-in-paris/le-select-brasserie" title="LeSelect">LeSelect</a> which is the cafe where famous artist, Picasso and some other famous people used to sit there and sip a cup of coffee. I find the staff there very friendly even though they speak very little English. So, I immediately orders a cup of Café au lait which is just coffee with milk. I really like the coffee here which is very smooth and not too strong like Italian coffee. In the cafe you can find a lot of people just sitting there sipping coffee or drinking wine and chat.</p>

<p>Then we went to <a href="http://www.cafedelapaix.fr/fr/index.php" title="Cafe de la paix">Cafe de la Paix</a> which is a cafe under InterContinental hotel. It’s famous for location which you can see the beautiful opera and even listen to some of the street performers in front of the Opera house. However, it’s a really touristy place which is why it’s very pricy. I wouldn’t recommend here if you’re on a budget, but if you want to sink yourself in to absorb the atmosphere. Then, you might want to try this Opera Cake. It’s really delicious with the vanilla sauce.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.noppanit.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Paris-With-P_Tong-98.jpg"><img src="https://www.noppanit.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Paris-With-P_Tong-98.jpg" alt="Paris With P_Tong-98" width="400" height="600" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1198" /></a></p>

<p>I moved on to supposedly one of the best Chocolatiers in Paris, <a href="http://www.jeanpaulhevin.com/fr/" title="Jean Paul Hevin">Jean-Paul Hévin</a>. We bought a box of macaroons and a bag of assortments. I can tell you this is the best macaroons I have ever tasted. I’m sure you can find far more tastier macaroons in French, but right now this is my number one. The macaroon is really crisp on the outside and soft on the inside. The filling is also really delicious. I can tell you if you’re looking for a box of macaroons for a gift, you won’t be disappointed if you get it from here.</p>

<p><a href="https://www.noppanit.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Paris-With-P_Tong-111.jpg"><img src="https://www.noppanit.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Paris-With-P_Tong-111.jpg" alt="Jean Paul Hevin" width="788" height="600" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1191" /></a></p>

<p><small><a style="color: #0000ff; text-align: left;" href="https://maps.google.com/maps?f=q&amp;source=embed&amp;hl=en&amp;geocode=&amp;q=Jean+Paul+H%C3%A9vin,+231+Rue+Saint-Honor%C3%A9,+Paris,+France&amp;aq=0&amp;oq=Jean+Paul+&amp;sll=37.0625,-95.677068&amp;sspn=56.243791,135.351563&amp;ie=UTF8&amp;hq=Jean+Paul+H%C3%A9vin,&amp;hnear=231+Rue+Saint-Honor%C3%A9,+75001+Paris,+%C3%8Ele-de-France,+France&amp;ll=48.866221,2.329219&amp;spn=0.006295,0.006295&amp;t=m">View Larger Map</a></small></p>

<p>We only have one day in Paris and that week was rainy the whole week. That’s why we didn’t really explore more of Paris plus we ate a lot and I mean a lot. Next time, I’ll definitely come back for more Cafe and good food.</p>

<p>Well, this probably is one of the worse UX design I have ever seen on a machine. I was trying to buy a ticket. The lady at the counter wouldn’t sell a ticket to me instead she pointed me to this machine. Which the buttons are not English and instead of up or down buttons. I had to rotate the rolling at the centre. Parisians might find this easy, but I struggled with the machine for 2 minutes. What do you think of the UI?</p>

<p><a href="https://www.noppanit.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Paris-With-P_Tong-255.jpg"><img src="https://www.noppanit.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/Paris-With-P_Tong-255.jpg" alt="Paris With P_Tong-255" width="800" height="533" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1193" /></a></p>

<blockquote>
  <p>Don’t come to Paris on Sunday. Most shops close on Sunday.</p>
</blockquote>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
