<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: performance | My Blog]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/blog/categories/performance/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-10-09T18:14:30-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.noppanit.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Noppanit Charassinvichai]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why algorithm matters?]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/why-algorithm-matters/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-08T15:55:29-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.noppanit.com/why-algorithm-matters</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have been to one of those technical interviews, you will like this.</p>

<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" lang="en"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">Google: 90% of our engineers use the software you wrote (Homebrew), but you can’t invert a binary tree on a whiteboard so fuck off.</p>&mdash; Max Howell (@mxcl) <a href="https://twitter.com/mxcl/status/608682016205344768">June 10, 2015</a></blockquote>


<script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>


<p>I&rsquo;m not going to rant about how broken the technical interviews are. There&rsquo;s enough people who are more qualified to rant about this more than me.</p>

<p>So, why this matters? I just want to give a quick example of why algorithm matters. Please no haters! I know some of you might read this and will say &ldquo;I do that all the time, what&rsquo;s the big deal&rdquo;. I&rsquo;m still a bad developer and I&rsquo;m still learning.</p>

<h2>Scenario</h2>

<p>You are a general, your home country is at war and you have to fight for your country. You are given a group of soldiers. You want to come up with a strategy to win the battle. Here&rsquo;s the example of the soldiers.</p>

<pre><code>[
    {
        "category": "machine-gun",
        "id": 0,
        "name": "D408CF"
    },
    {
        "category": "machine-gun",
        "id": 1,
        "name": "C0BAD7"
    },
    {
        "category": "rocket-man",
        "id": 2,
        "name": "04B5E4"
    },
    {
        "category": "rocket-man",
        "id": 3,
        "name": "22F3CF"
    },
    {
        "category": "machine-gun",
        "id": 4,
        "name": "811E8A"
    }
    ,
    ...
]
</code></pre>

<p>You came out of a high-profile meeting and all the generals agree that this formation will be best to fight the enemy; <em>infantry</em>, <em>machine-gun</em> and <em>rocket-man</em>. How can I rearrange this quick enough because we&rsquo;re going to attack tomorrow? Simple I go ahead and write the code.</p>

<p>First, let&rsquo;s generate a bunch of soldiers</p>

<pre><code class="python">class Soldier(object):
    def __init__(self, id, name, category):
        self.id = id
        self.name = name
        self.category = category

number_of_soldier = 10000

soldiers = []
for i in range(0, number_of_soldier):
    name = str(uuid.uuid4().get_hex().upper()[0:6])
    soldiers.append(Soldier(i, name, random.choice(categories)))
</code></pre>

<p>Then let&rsquo;s rearrange them.</p>

<pre><code class="python">import json
import uuid
import random
import time

categories = ['infantry', 'machine-gun', 'rocket-man']

start = time.time()
result = []
for c in categories:
    s_list = []
    for s in soldiers:
        if s.category == c:
            s_list.append(s)

    result.extend(s_list)
    s_list = []

end = time.time()
print(end - start)
</code></pre>

<p>It works, but you&rsquo;re too late you can&rsquo;t form the soldiers in time. If you take a closer look, this algorithm takes <em>O(n</em>m)<em> for the time complexity given the number of soldiers is </em>n<em> and the </em>category<em> is </em>m<em>. If you have a million soldiers and a million categories you would get </em>O(n<sup>2</sup>)*. How can we make this one faster?</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s my second version. Hmm, rearrange into category&hellip; category is bucket. How about using map?</p>

<pre><code class="python">from collections import defaultdict

start = time.time()
map_of_soldiers = defaultdict(list)

for s in soldiers:
    map_of_soldiers[s.category].append(s)

result = []
for c in categories:
    result.extend(map_of_soldiers.get(c))

end = time.time()
print(end - start)
</code></pre>

<p>This is the time difference of those two algorithms.</p>

<pre><code>0.00743103027344
0.00331783294678
</code></pre>

<p>By just changing the data structure, you can see that the <em>map</em> version is almost twice as fast. I hope I can demostrate how choosing the right algorithm matters in your program.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octopress on crack]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/octopress-on-crack/"/>
    <updated>2015-10-07T22:44:22-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.noppanit.com/octopress-on-crack</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I believe you will find a ton of blogs writing about makeing Octopress faster. I believe nearly everyone who migrated their blog to Octopress, the first post would be the migration and the next would be performance tuning. I want to be the cool kid so here you go.</p>

<p>Once you got out of WordPress now there&rsquo;s much more you can do about your performance. But before you start, nothing can be done before you have the baseline numbers</p>

<h2>Before</h2>

<p>Here&rsquo;s my before performance from Google PageSpeed.</p>

<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/google-pagespeed-before.jpg" title="Google PageSpeed before performance" ></p>

<p>And from webpagetest.org</p>

<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/before-perf-noppanit-com.jpg" title="Webpagetest before performance" ></p>

<p>In a nutshell, my page starts to render in <em>2.4s</em> and finishes in <em>4s</em>. Yikes! I wouldn&rsquo;t even want to wait for my site to load. Let&rsquo;s see where&rsquo;s the lowest hanging fruit.</p>

<h2>What about images?</h2>

<p>A picture is worth a thousand words. Who doesn&rsquo;t like image right? Also, I tend to have a lot of screenshots and they&rsquo;re all PNGs. And they tend to be big. As they&rsquo;re all screenshots so I don&rsquo;t really care about losing some of the quality so I convert them to be jpg. If you&rsquo;re using OSX, there&rsquo;s a command that you can run.</p>

<pre><code>sips -s format jpeg your_png.png --out your_pic.jpg
</code></pre>

<p>Now what can we do to reduce the size? There&rsquo;s lots of tools out there that you can just throw your image in and it will compress the image for you. I use <a href="https://compressor.io/">compressor.io</a>. It&rsquo;s really good. Just try throwing your image in there and see what happens. Compressor.io can reduce my images up to 60% and that saves a lot of bandwidth.</p>

<h2>Minify CSS/JS</h2>

<p>Fortunetely, I use <a href="https://www.cloudflare.com/">Cloudflare</a> and they have the feature to minify that for you. So, I just flipped the switch and it works like magic.</p>

<h2>Browser caching</h2>

<p>Going back to what Google PageSpeed tells us again. It complaints about <em>Leverage browser caching</em>. I&rsquo;m lucky again because in Cloudflare you can set the cache to be 30 days and that seems to be ok for Google.</p>

<h2>Inline CSS</h2>

<p>I use <a href="https://github.com/tommy351/Octopress-Theme-Slash">Slash</a> theme and when I look at the CSS, it&rsquo;s only 22K. So why not just inline it and save one more request for the browser. So, in <em>_includes/head.html</em> you can change the line that includes your stylesheet to be.</p>

<p><figure class='code'><figcaption><span>html </span></figcaption>
<div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
<span class='line-number'>3</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>&lt;style>
</span><span class='line'>        {\% include screen.css %} # delete &lsquo;\&rsquo; in front of % before you paste this snippet
</span><span class='line'>    &lt;/style></span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></p>

<p>This might be different from theme to theme but it shouldn&rsquo;t be difficult to find that out.</p>

<h2>After</h2>

<p>Now, let&rsquo;s have a quick look at the after performance.</p>

<p>Here&rsquo;s my after performance from Google PageSpeed.</p>

<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/google-pagespeed-after.jpg" title="Google PageSpeed after" ></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s a lot better now but there&rsquo;s one tiny problem with mobile which I&rsquo;ll write another blog post about that.</p>

<p>Let&rsquo;s have a look at webpagetest now.</p>

<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2015/10/webpagetest-after.jpg" title="Webpagetest After" ></p>

<p>A lot better! It&rsquo;s still not the best but now my page loads within <em>0.5s</em> and finishes in <em>1.9s</em>. However, there&rsquo;s still a lot to work on mobile.</p>

<p>I could shead about 200ms by not using SSL but I&rsquo;m willing to compromise that with a little bit of security.</p>

<h2>What&rsquo;s next</h2>

<p>I&rsquo;d like to try hosting the images on S3 to see if that would speed up the load time. And I want to make the images responsive for mobile.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
