<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: resolutions | My Blog]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/blog/categories/resolutions/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/"/>
  <updated>2017-08-28T21:59:09-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.noppanit.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Noppanit Charassinvichai]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2016]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/2016/"/>
    <updated>2016-01-01T11:29:38-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.noppanit.com/2016</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h2 id="goals-for-2016">Goals for 2016</h2>

<p>I want to make this a habit for me that I want to make goals for every year and commit to them. So, here’s what I want to achieve in 2016.</p>

<h3 id="fitness-psychically-and-mentally">Fitness, psychically and mentally.</h3>

<p>I know everyone makes this a New Year resolution. But I really want to make this true this year. I’m not much overweight and I lift. I’m really into 5x5 program and I’ve just busted my plateau from last year. This year, I want to be more consistent. Another important thing is I’m going to run a marathon this year as I didn’t do it last year even if it’s just going to be me.</p>

<p>Progress
1. Squat 185lb
2. Oh Press 80lb
3. Deadlift 265lb
4. Barbell Row 170lb</p>

<p>I’d like to increase every move by at least 25lb by the end of this year.</p>

<p>The most important thing for me this year is my mental hygiene. When I was a monk, I used to meditate 30 minutes a day but once I got out of it I never did it. I’m going to make this my mission to meditate 10-15 minutes a day before going to bed. I added this as my daily habit on my habitica.</p>

<p><img src="/wp-content/uploads/2016/01/habitica.png"></p>

<p>This resolution kinda sums everything that I want 2016 to be. I just want to be a happy me. If something’s going to create more stress I’m just going to say no.</p>

<h3 id="reach-level-of-my-fluency-in-spanish">Reach level of my fluency in Spanish</h3>

<p>I’ve just started learning Spanish a couple months ago and I like the language. There’s levels of fluency but I want to be able to make at least basic conversation. I should be comfortable ordering meals in Spanish restaurants in New York city. I’m planning to travel in South America and I would like to be able to make conversation with local people. I don’t want to be able to read news or make business conversation.</p>

<h3 id="become-a-data-scientist">Become a Data Scientist</h3>

<p>It wouldn’t be complete without a technical goal. I’ve just changed my career as my interests in data grew. Now I’m a Data Engineer. My day to day job is to create and maintain data pipeline for an organization. I still build stuff but it’s just different product. I like my job now but I would like to get involved more in the science. I’m taking Statistics courses and learning some algorithms to analyse a large dataset. I don’t have a degree in maths so it’s going to be a challenge for me but hey challenge accepted.</p>

<h3 id="travel">Travel</h3>

<p>I know this is everyone’s resolution. I have been to a lot of countries when I was working with ThoughtWorks. I’d like to go to less countries but spend more time to learn the culture and talking to local people. I used to just go to different countries to hangout by the bar or restaurant but this year I’m going to make less trips but more meaningful.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
