<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: retrospective | My Blog]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/blog/categories/retrospective/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-12-30T21:00:35-05:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.noppanit.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Noppanit Charassinvichai]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Retrospective 2015]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/retrospective-2015/"/>
    <updated>2015-12-24T14:26:19-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.noppanit.com/retrospective-2015</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="reflections-on-2015-posturl-2015-02-05-2015-">Reflections on <a href="/2015/">2015</a></h1>

<ul>
  <li>I gotta say that my big win for 2015 is I deleted most of my social media accounts even I didn’t plan on doing that at all. I deleted my FB account a couple times in the past. I ended up getting it back. I increase Signal to Noise ration a lot by just deleting that. I used to spend at least 1-2 hour(s) on Facebook browsing what my friends have been doing. Sometimes, I got depressed because it seemed like all the people on Facebook they are on expensive vacation trips.</li>
</ul>

<p>At first, I was worried because I wouldn’t be able to get in touch with some of my friends and family. But I still talk to my family. We have LINE Messanger which we share pictures and videos. And all of friends that want to contact me, they always find a way to contact me if they want to contact me. I didn’t feel left out at all.</p>

<p>One of the main reasons that I don’t seem to like Facebook as it’s been abused a lot. My mum is the best example, she reacts aggresively and unnecessary to political opinions.</p>

<ul>
  <li>
    <p>I didn’t have any excuse for not running the Chicago Marathon but myself to blame. I didn’t train hard enough. I deferred it until 2016 and that would be my 2016 Resolutions.</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I did learn Spanish. I signed up for the beginner class and now I’m on the second level. Yo hablo poco Espanol!</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I didn’t learn to invest at all. But my knowledge on how to survive in the US has improved a lot (After spending almost $500 on my medical bill).</p>
  </li>
  <li>
    <p>I went to Peru and it was awesome! I highly recommened anyone to do it.</p>
  </li>
</ul>

<h1 id="summary">Summary</h1>

<h2 id="move-to-the-us">Move to the US</h2>
<p>I moved to the US a year ago. I didn’t regret the decision at all. I joined Fusion Media Network in 2015 as a Developer. However, as my curiosity in Data Science grows. I decided to join Condé Nast as a Data Engineer to quench my curiosity. It feels weird for the first month not building a website or web service. But I got to learn a whole new side of Engineering.</p>

<h2 id="kollaboration">Kollaboration</h2>
<p>I joined <a href="http://www.kollab.nyc/">Kollaboration</a> as a Technical Director to help out my friend. Unfortunetely, I failed on Time management and I didn’t have enough time to contribute. I’ll devote 2016 to improve my Time management skill.</p>

<h2 id="germany">Germany</h2>
<p>I met with a bunch of ex-Thoughtworker friends in Germany and I had a blast. I realised how much I love spending time in Germany. I love Berlin and I love the culture over there. People are nice and the coffee is the best I’ve had anywhere. I also received the saddest news whilst I was in Germany.</p>

<h2 id="thailand">Thailand</h2>
<p>I spoke in <a href="http://www.agiletourbkk.org/">Agile Tour Bangkok 2015</a>. My talk wasn’t that popular because I was up against with some big names but I did send my message to the audience and I got some positive feedback.</p>

<h2 id="habit">Habit</h2>
<p>I found the <a href="https://habitica.com">task management</a> board that works for me. I didn’t say it’s the best because certainly it lacks a lot of features but it works for me. Will have to come up with another post for this one.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
