<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Culinary | My Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://noppanit.github.io/blog/categories/culinary/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://noppanit.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-10-01T16:31:21-04:00</updated>
  <id>http://noppanit.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Noppanit Charassinvichai]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[My Quest to Find My Perfect Brew.]]></title>
    <link href="http://noppanit.github.io/my-quest-to-find-my-perfect-brew/"/>
    <updated>2013-08-19T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://noppanit.github.io/my-quest-to-find-my-perfect-brew</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have found this definition of programmer which is really funny and true.</p>

<blockquote><p>Programmer n. (proh-gram-er) an organism that turns caffeine and pizza into software</p></blockquote>

<p>. You can order this lousy T-Shirt <a href="http://www.zazzle.com/programmer_definition_t_shirt-235878094715752076">here</a>.</p>

<p>I know everybody loves a cup of Joe. I&#8217;m amazed when people order decaf coffee which I have to resist myself to ask this question every time, &#8220;Why on earth you want to drink that?&#8221;, I&#8217;m sure most people who are coffee fanatic will ask the same question. Well, that&#8217;s the purpose of this blog here. I love coffee and I love it dark, rich and no milk. Now my love for coffee grows and I cannoy quench my thirst for a perfect cup with my french press anymore, so I seek help from professionals.</p>

<p>So far, I have been drinking my coffee from <a href="http://www.monmouthcoffee.co.uk/" title="monmouth coffee">Monmouth</a> in London, which I&#8217;m sure people love them and lucky me my office is just 5 min walk to the coffee shop. But what about at home? How do I drink the same quality coffee at home. Like most people, when I was a student I could not afford a £2 cup of coffee. My coffee intake had always come from instant coffee. Now I have (not so much) money I can enjoy what I love drinking the most. I started with filter coffee which you can buy filters from supermarket. They&#8217;re cheap and you can make a decent coffee if done it right. However, I don&#8217;t want to buy new filters every week considering how much I drink coffee everyday. Until my girlfriend gave me this as my birthday present with ground coffee from Starbucks (I know, I know but hey that was my first ground coffee). My life has changed you just pour ground coffee and in with hot water wait for a couple minutes and plunge and enjoy!</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s my setting so far.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.noppanit.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/French-Press-5.jpg"><img src="http://www.noppanit.com/wp-content/uploads/2013/08/French-Press-5.jpg" alt="French Press" class="aligncenter size-full wp-image-1142 cool_border" /></a></p>

<p>My quest has not stopped there. I decided to take a further step by taking up a Barista course at <a href="http://www.taylor-st.com/home-barista-course" title="TAylor">taylor</a>. I have learned more about coffee origins, cupping, how to stream milk and good ratio for espresso.</p>

<p>Here&#8217;s my take from the course which I think it was really comprehensive.</p>

<ul>
<li>Never buy ground coffee, once the coffee has been grinned it&#8217;s losing its aroma and quality.</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t stock up your coffee, buy small batch and don&#8217;t keep it longer than 6 months.</li>
<li>Good ratio for espresso and water is 1:1.2, but you need to find your golden ratio. And it&#8217;s different for every coffee. So, if you try new coffee you need to adjust your balance.</li>
<li>Don&#8217;t freeze your coffee, think of it as your spice.</li>
<li>Grind size, does and time matter a lot to your coffee</li>
</ul>


<p>After I have learned all of this I changed my way of making coffee. I still cannot afford a decent espresso machine but I know how to tune up my way of making coffee. I used to just put some 2-3 table spoons of coffee and boiling water and then plunge it right away. Sometime I over-extracted the coffee by letting the coffee submerged too long. Here&#8217;s some of the steps I have changed.</p>

<p>I still haven&#8217;t got a decent grinder so I&#8217;m still relying on my ground coffee from supermarket. I&#8217;ll buy a grinder soon which I&#8217;ll blog about that later.</p>

<ul>
<li>Instead of putting 2-3 table spoons of coffee, I weight it around 16-20 grams.</li>
<li>Instead of using boiling water, I put the kettle on, let it boil and after the switch is cut I leave it there for ~2 minutes so the temp drops to around 90. I remember went I bought a cup of coffee from big chained coffee shop and I had to let the coffee sit there for 10 minutes before I could even sip it.</li>
<li>Instead of guessing the amount of water, I use around 240mm for a cup of coffee. (This is not for espresso though).</li>
<li>Stir the coffee twice to make sure that all the coffee is submerged.</li>
<li>Instead of extract the coffee for sometime, I time it for 3:30 minutes and the last 30 seconds I just plunge and pour the coffee right away.</li>
</ul>


<p>I was really surprised how much my cup of Joe has changed even though I didn&#8217;t change the coffee or even my french press.</p>

<p>However, I&#8217;m not going to stop just there, my quest continues. Now, I&#8217;m looking for a decent Espresso machine for my home brew&#8230;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Best Schweinshaxe I&#8217;ve Ever Eaten So Far Yet in Munich.]]></title>
    <link href="http://noppanit.github.io/best-schweinshaxe-ive-ever-eaten-so-far-yet-in-munich/"/>
    <updated>2012-09-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://noppanit.github.io/best-schweinshaxe-ive-ever-eaten-so-far-yet-in-munich</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, as the title says this was the best Pork Knuckles I have ever eaten in Munich, Germany. I love food and I love good food. So I always find good restaurants, sometimes I go for a michelin-star restaurant but you can&#8217;t do that everyday. I was in Okterber Fest in Munich last week, but it was raining so I decided to find something bavarian to eat instead. I googled for a few and I decided to go for this place &#8220;<a href="https://maps.google.co.uk/maps?q=haxnbauer&amp;ll=48.137515,11.578635&amp;spn=0.003064,0.006968&amp;fb=1&amp;gl=uk&amp;hq=haxnbauer&amp;cid=0,0,7797826227648288280&amp;t=m&amp;z=18&amp;iwloc=A">Haxnbauer</a>&#8220;. They don&#8217;t have a website so this is the only link I can find.</p>

<p><a href="#"><img src="http://www.noppanit.com/wp-content/uploads/2012/09/IMG_7793_edited-1-300x199.jpg" alt="" title="Schweinshaxe" width="300" height="199" class="alignnone size-medium wp-image-873 cool_border" /></a></p>

<p>The cracking is crispy and the sauce is just right with the meat. With Weissbier is just perfect.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Perfect Roast Chicken]]></title>
    <link href="http://noppanit.github.io/the-perfect-roast-chicken/"/>
    <updated>2008-03-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://noppanit.github.io/the-perfect-roast-chicken</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I have watched Heston Blumenthal and liked him very much. I tried some dishes from the program which is the perfect roast chicken. It was work very well. I used the technique which is called &#8220;low-temperature cooking&#8221;. This technique use low temperature and long time to cook. Moreover, there are some techniques that I used from the program which I&#8217;ll show in this article. This dish use a whole organic chicken and approximately 1 day to cook.</p>

<ol>
<li>Soak the poultry in 8% slated water for 6 hours.</li>
<li>After 6 hour, soak the poultry in cold water for 1 hour, but change the water every 15 minutes.</li>
<li>After 1 hour, plunge the poultry into boiling water for just 30 seconds and plunge into iced water to stop the heat penetrate into the poultry. Do this process 2 times. This process makes poultry to more succulent and juicy.</li>
<li>Dry the skin with tissue paper and leave it in the fridge for 1 day. This process makes the skin crispier.</li>
<li>Roast the poultry in the oven for at least 3 hours at 60C. Use thermometer the measure whether the poultry cooked or not. Make sure that the deepest of the poultry stay at 60C at least 15 minutes. You will please with this result.<br/>
6 However, this technique doesn&#8217;t brown the skin. You can fried the skin later if you want.</li>
</ol>


<p><img src="http://i2.photobucket.com/albums/y41/newbie_toy/IMG_2773.jpg" alt="" /><br/>
This chicken uses the above technique. The skin was crispy and the flesh was juicy and succulent. When I carved the poultry, I could see all of the juice came out. It was superb.</p>

<p><img src="http://i2.photobucket.com/albums/y41/newbie_toy/IMG_2805.jpg" alt="" /><br/>
This chicken I didn&#8217;t use the above technique. I could see the different between those two. When I carved the poultry, the flesh was soft but not succulent, because all the juice come out duringroasting time. I could see the fat sitting at the bottom of the tray.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Best Hot Chocolate]]></title>
    <link href="http://noppanit.github.io/the-best-hot-chocolate/"/>
    <updated>2008-03-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://noppanit.github.io/the-best-hot-chocolate</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This is the best chocolate I have ever taste.</p>

<p>Ingredients<br/>
1. Chocolate powder<br/>
2. Semi-skimmed milk<br/>
3. Chocolate moose</p>

<ol>
<li>Simmer semi-skimmed milk until you can see a little bubbles come out, but not boil it until the boiling point</li>
<li>2 tablespoons of chocolate powder and add the simmering milk</li>
<li>decorate chocolate moose on top of the chocolate milk</li>
<li>sprinkle a little bit of chocolate powder as in the picture</li>
</ol>


<p><a href="http://www.noppanit.com/cooking/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/img_2363.jpg" title="Direct link to file"><img src="http://www.noppanit.com/cooking/wp-content/uploads/2007/12/img_2363.thumbnail.jpg" alt="The best hot chocolate" height="128" width="162" /></a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Alternative Medicine Cabinet]]></title>
    <link href="http://noppanit.github.io/the-alternative-medicine-cabinet/"/>
    <updated>2008-03-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://noppanit.github.io/the-alternative-medicine-cabinet</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Cabbage: for food poisoning<br/>
</strong>Well-cooked cabbage and the water it&#8217;s been boiled in are effective at clearing up minor diarrhoea and sickness caused by food poisoning. &#8220;White cabbage, in particular, is very high in sulphur, which helps destroy harmful bacteria in your stomach,&#8221; says Susie Perry from nutrition therapy clinic Smart Nutrition. Try to eat at least three large tablespoons of thoroughly boiled leaves, or sip a cup of the cooking water.</p>

<p><strong>Walnuts: for winter blues</strong><br/>
&#8220;Walnuts are a fantastic source of zinc, amino acids and omega 3 and 6, which help prevent depression,&#8221; says pharmacist Margo Marrone of the Organic Pharmacy, which is dedicated to organic health and beauty treatments. &#8220;Walnuts influence the levels of serotonin in the brain and help to nourish the nervous system. You should aim to eat a small handful every day. &#8221; Other feelgood foods include flax seed, almonds and sunflower seeds, which are high in tryptophan, an essential amino acid that increases the production of serotonin.</p>

<p><strong>Cinnamon: for bloating and indigestion<br/>
</strong>Research has shown that this aromatic spice helps inhibit the growth or E coli when added to food. It encourages the digestive system to work efficiently and can be used to treat indigestion and flatulence. &#8216;And because it improves appetite, it&#8217;s also an effective herb to use when recovering from a cold or flu,&#8217; says medical herbalist Dr An Walker. Stir a half-teaspoon of powder into a warm drink or porridge every morning.?? Use only small amounts and do not take it you&#8217;re pregnant.</p>

<p><strong>Horse Chestnut: for aching joints and muscles<br/>
</strong>Horse chestnut strengthens the walls of small blood vessels and helps treat aching muscles, varicose veins and swollen ankles caused by weakened veins.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
