<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Digital Camera | My Blog]]></title>
  <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/blog/categories/digital-camera/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/"/>
  <updated>2015-10-02T15:31:04-04:00</updated>
  <id>https://www.noppanit.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Noppanit Charassinvichai]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to Shoot Astrophotography for Absolute Dummies, Like Me.]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/shoot-astrophotography-absolute-dummies-like/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-18T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.noppanit.com/shoot-astrophotography-absolute-dummies-like</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ok, no more murmur I will just cut to the chest. It&#8217;s because I&#8217;m not really a professional and my picture is far from professional, but it&#8217;s a good starting point to any one hasn&#8217;t done it before.</p>

<h2>Equipments</h2>

<ol>
<li>Tripod</li>
<li>DSLR</li>
</ol>


<h2>How to?</h2>

<ol>
<li>Find the darkest and clear night, full moon won&#8217;t work. Also, if you live in the city then go out. City light will just noise your dark sky.</li>
<li>Mount your camera to the tripod</li>
<li>Start with ISO 800</li>
<li>Widest aperture, start with F4</li>
<li>Manual focus and adjust to infinity</li>
<li>Here&#8217;s a little trick, there&#8217;s a 500 or 600 rule. The idea is to divide 500 or 600 with your focal length. For example, if you are at 18mm then 500/18 = 27. That&#8217;s your shutter speed. This is to prevent any star trail.</li>
<li>Adjust one thing at a time. For example, ISO first and then aperture to get your best results.</li>
</ol>


<p>Have fun! Play with your settings.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Have Found My Perfect Travel Tripod. Manfrotto Befree]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/found-perfect-travel-tripod-manfrotto-befree/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-17T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.noppanit.com/found-perfect-travel-tripod-manfrotto-befree</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This might just be me and this blog post is just my opinion and just give people another opinion if they&#8217;re interested in buying a travel tripod. I&#8217;m sure you will own either one or two tripods if you&#8217;re a serious photographer. Even if you&#8217;re not there&#8217;s a chance that you will own at least one. I have one as well, but very clunky and heavy which I got it really cheap because of the heavy material. And I thought I didn&#8217;t mind to carry it around I can just put it in a car. However, I rarely take it with me when I&#8217;m on a trip. Why? because as you travel a lot, you tend to travel light and those tripods won&#8217;t fit in your suitcase. Also, you don&#8217;t want to carry huge tripod around the airport, I learnt that the hard way when I was in India. I needed to get my tripod scanned and wrapped and scanned again. They had to make sure I could not dissemble my tripod to be a weapon or some sort. It was fun though.</p>

<p>Now I have found this, <a href="http://www.manfrotto.com/befree" title="Manfrotto Befree">Manfrotto Befree</a>. Why I think it&#8217;s perfect for me. Because I can fit that in my suitcase so I won&#8217;t have any problem carrying it with me on a trip and it&#8217;s really small so I will have less trouble carrying it with me when I&#8217;m hiking. However, it&#8217;s not carbon fibre so it won&#8217;t be super light, but because of its size it&#8217;s not too heavy. I can carry it with my 5D all day.</p>

<p>That&#8217;s the best bit for a travel tripod. However, you won&#8217;t use that for a 9-hour long exposure for sure as it&#8217;s not that sturdy but for taking night views with not-so-long exposure or even fireworks it works really well. So, it&#8217;s just another opinion if you&#8217;re thinking of buying a travel tripod.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How I Learn to Love Mode &#8220;M&#8221; in DSLR.]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/learn-to-love-mode-m-dslr/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-16T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.noppanit.com/learn-to-love-mode-m-dslr</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>If you have a DSLR or any mirror-less camera, there&#8217;s a good chance that you will have this &#8220;M&#8221; mode. It&#8217;s a mode where you can control shutter speed or aperture. It sounds scary for most people because at first I think I bought this quite expensive camera I think it should know best what&#8217;s good for my pictures. Mostly I want to just use either &#8220;A&#8221; for everyday shoot or &#8220;S&#8221; if I really want to control my shutter speed but rarely I use this mode. But after I have attended a flash photography course and learned to use &#8220;M&#8221; mode for a flash gun, the reason that the teacher gave us was that it consumes less battery which I think it&#8217;s not the case for camera. I was hooked up and how easy to use &#8220;M&#8221; mode and I transferred that knowledge to my DSLR.</p>

<h2>Why &#8220;M&#8221; mode is good?</h2>

<p>I think this is quite personal. And if you have read blogs from most professionals they will suggest you should try &#8220;M&#8221; mode for better results or just to get used to it. I have been ignored that advice for years. Personally, the good things about manual mode is that you have control over your camera. Also, when you use a flash gun your camera doesn&#8217;t know it. If you shoot in dark and use &#8220;A&#8221; mode your camera will measure the light as very dark and will try to adjust your shutter speed lower. Another good point for me is that it&#8217;s easier and more granular to adjust your stop than exposure. For example, if you shoot in &#8220;A&#8221; or &#8220;S&#8221; and you think your picture is either over or under exposure you will try to increase or decrease your exposure and sometimes I feel like it&#8217;s not what I really want after adjusted it, but adjusting either shutter speed or aperture to me feels more natural.</p>

<h2>How I shoot in &#8220;M&#8221; mode</h2>

<p>First I look at the light conditions to use my judgement about my lights. If it&#8217;s sunny I will base my aperture between F5.6 to F8 or even F11 and then shutter speed around 1/250 so my picture won&#8217;t get blurry. Then I shoot. Then I see if I like it or not, if not I will adjust either aperture or shutter speed. Remember to adjust one thing at a time, because it&#8217;s easier to remember. Luckily, we shoot in digital now so we can erase unwanted images immediately. If I&#8217;m comfortable with the picture now I will shoot with that settings until the light conditions change and start the process again. For example, if suddenly a cloud is in the way they you need to go up one or two stops. Practice like this for a day and you will get used to it gradually. I think it&#8217;s much more fun.</p>

<p>If it&#8217;s a bit shady or poor light conditions I will increase my ISO first to 400 or 600 then repeat the same process.</p>

<p><strong>Updated</strong> As my colleague pointed out after a few hours, the point is to have fun and play with your camera. Enjoy his <a href="http://3oheme.com/blog/2013/06/26/please-have-fun-with-your-camera.html" title="Have fun with your camera">post</a> which is to have fun with &#8220;A&#8221; or &#8220;S&#8221; mode.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Tips &#8211; How to Photograph Fireworks Displays]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/tips-how-to-photograph-fireworks-displays/"/>
    <updated>2009-11-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.noppanit.com/tips-how-to-photograph-fireworks-displays</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img class="alignnone" title="Fireworks photography" src="http://i2.photobucket.com/albums/y41/newbie_toy/20091107_Fireworks_0087-1.jpg" alt="" width="400" height="300" /></p>

<p>Well, The Guy Fawkes has just passed. I actually don&#8217;t know what is Guy Fawkes day, I only know that there was a guy who wanted to blow the Westminister up. And that&#8217;s it. However, I know that there are gonna be some fireworks displays all over the UK. So, I have to get ready and this is my first attempt to shoot fireworks displays. I have researched and prepared all the things for the shoot.</p>

<p><strong>Equipments</strong></p>

<ol>
<li>A decent tripod, this is a must if you don&#8217;t want your bloom to be blurred.</li>
<li>A good location, it should be some places where you could place your tripod and use the widest lens you could find to try to capture all the bloom and may be the event.</li>
<li>A remote shutter to prevent from camera shaking, I tried to use the mirror-lock functionality or timer, but by the time you wait for 2 secs or 1 secs, the bloom just gone. The fireworks wont&#8217; last long. So, be prepared.</li>
</ol>


<p><strong>Techniques</strong></p>

<ol>
<li>Set your camera to M mode, so you could control your aperture and shutter speed.</li>
<li>Set your lens to the widest angle.</li>
<li>Set your F to 11</li>
<li>Set your shutter speed to 2 secs or 1 sec.</li>
<li>Set your focus to auto and try roughly where the fireworks will go up, and change to Manual focus so the focus won&#8217;t change while you&#8217;re shooting.</li>
<li>Try shooting some of the first blooms and see the results. If it&#8217;s too static or blurred, you&#8217;ll need to set the shutter slower or faster respectively.</li>
<li>If the shot is too bright or too dark, leave the shutter speed alone and dial in a higher or lower F/number respectively.</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[HowTo : CPL Filter]]></title>
    <link href="https://www.noppanit.com/howto-cpl-filter/"/>
    <updated>2007-07-17T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>https://www.noppanit.com/howto-cpl-filter</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This topic I will record about how to use CPL filter, because I have bought this filter about 5 months. However, I couldn&#8217;t use it well, until now.</p>

<p>The source of light coming from right hand. Therefore, I turned the ring on the filter directed to the source of light.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.noppanit.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/07/img_9672-before.JPG" title="Before Filtering"><img src="http://www.noppanit.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/07/img_9672-before.thumbnail.JPG" alt="Before Filtering" /></a><br/>
This picture took before I used CPL filter.</p>

<p><a href="http://www.noppanit.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/07/img_9671-after.JPG" title="After Filtering"><img src="http://www.noppanit.com/wp-content/uploads/2007/07/img_9671-after.thumbnail.JPG" alt="After Filtering" /></a><br/>
This picture took after I used CPL filter, you can see how is this filter make and effect to the Notebook</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
